Provided by sash35
Modify by Blue-Bird™
Hey.
Hmm?
That's right. It is I, Tai Lung.
It can't be.
Tai Lung.
I have returned to take what is mine.
Which is everything that is yours.
Let it be known from the highest mountain
to the lowest valley that Tai Lung lives,
and no one will stand in his way.
Not even the great Dragon Warrior.
Oh, where is Po?
He was supposed to be here hours ago.
Ping, will you please just relax?
I am relaxed!
Okay. I'm sure Po is fine.
But what if he's sick? What if he's hurt?
- What if he's hungry?
Don't get your noodles in a twist.
If I know our son, he's probably just
kicking back and catching some rays.
Kung fu!
Whoa! That's bad.
Whoa! Getting worse.
Whoa!
Ah, come on!
Ha-ha!
Okay, big guy.
We're really gonna have to wrap this up.
Whee!
- Oink.
- Again, again!
- That was fun.
- Let's do that again.
And next time,
keep your surf off their turf.
I'm late. I'm late. Ooh, I'm late.
The Dragon Warrior is back!
- It's the Dragon Warrior!
Was, is and always will be.
We love you, Dragon Warrior!
And I love you too, adoring fan.
Sign my scroll.
Sign my hat.
- Sign my shirt.
Okay, okay.
I'll sign whatever you want.
Po!
Master Shifu!
Here, let me just--
There, that's much... worse.
We have to talk.
Absolutely. Let's talk.
Right after the ceremony.
- Let's go!
- Ceremony?
What ceremony?
The Staff of Wisdom.
Ooh.
- Given to me by Master Oogway himself.
Aah.
It is said that
whoever possesses this staff
has the power
to travel between the realms.
The power to unlock the door
to the Spirit Realm.
And now, the power to open...
the all-new
Dragon Warrior Noodles and Tofu.
Where the broth has kick
and the bean curd's a knockout.
Dragon Warrior!
Will the Furious Five be here too?
Unfortunately, no.
They're off on
super cool kung fu missions.
Tigress is taking on
the free-range chicken gang.
Monkey's hot on the trail
of the missing macaque.
Crane was crowned
king of the Crocodilians.
Crane!
Long story.
Viper's wrapping up peace talks
between the cobras and the mongooses.
Or is it mongeese?
And Mantis?
Well, he's just trying to keep his
blushing bride from biting his head off.
Just 'cause they're not here in person
doesn't mean they're not here
as life-sized cut-outs.
Now, who wants a picture?
Okay, okay. One at a time.
- Oh! Me, me, me! Me!
- You.
My turn! My turn!
And then you.
He really captured
your disapproving scowl.
We need to talk.
- Now.
Hey, can I get one of those
in a wallet size?
Po!
- Coming.
Do you remember the first time you climbed
these steps to the Jade Palace?
How could I forget?
I thought I'd never make it to the top.
Yes, but you persevered.
And once again, destiny calls for you
to take the next step on your journey.
The next step?
What are you talking about?
I've already taken all the steps.
Haven't I?
It is time for you
to choose your successor.
Successor for what?
A successor to be
the next Dragon Warrior.
Oh... [chuckles] Yeah, I get it.
Funny, 'cause I'm the Dragon Warrior.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait, wait.
You mean, I'm not gonna be
the Dragon Warrior anymore?
- Exactly.
- Then what am I gonna be?
Once a successor is chosen,
you will advance
to the highest level in all of kung fu.
Spiritual Leader
of the Valley of Peace.
Whoa.
I don't know what that means.
It's just like
Master Oogway before you.
You will oversee the Valley,
passing along wisdom and inspiring hope.
Look, I appreciate the promotion.
I think I'm just gonna stick with
the whole "Dragon Warrior" thing.
Dragon Warrior "thing"?
What is it you're holding?
A cookie.
Other hand.
The Staff of Wisdom.
It was given to you
by Master Oogway.
Do you really think it was so you could
open a restaurant?
Or pose for pictures?
He wasn't super specific.
Oogway entrusted you with that staff
so you could follow in his footsteps
and become something better
than you already are.
You take it.
No. Oogway did not give it to me.
Being the next Oogway is not my destiny,
which I have accepted
and am at peace with.
- Really. It's fine.
- You don't sound fine.
- You don't sound fine! I'm very fine!
- Okay, you're fine.
This is an honor.
Oogway chose you as his successor,
and now you must choose yours.
Master Shifu,
I finally found something I'm good at,
and now you want to
just take it away from me?
No one is taking anything away, Po.
Who you are will always be
a part of what you become.
Yeah, but where's the "skadoosh"?
You know what I mean?
The "shasha-booie"?
I don't want to seem ungrateful,
but I don't know anything
about passing on wisdom or inspiring hope.
All I know are two things.
Kicking butt and taking names.
And if I'm being completely honest,
I'm not even that good at the name-taking.
Like, who was
that fire-breathing crocodile?
I wanna say Steve...
You were chosen
to bring peace to the Valley,
and there are other ways to bring peace
than simply kicking butt.
Well, sure. But not any fun ones.
Please. Being the Dragon Warrior
is all I know.
- It's who I am.
- Not anymore.
The Valley of Peace needs
a Spiritual Leader,
and Master Oogway chose you.
You'll start interviewing candidates
first thing tomorrow morning.
Candidates? What candidates?
Awesome!
No way!
Wow!
Skadoosh.
Fantastic pose.
Whoo-hoo! Nice.
Master Po will now choose
the next Dragon Warrior.
Dragon Warrior! Dragon Warrior!
So many great candidates.
I'm gonna let the finger decide.
Wait. Whoa. Whoa.
What is happening?
The Dragon Warrior. It's me!
Like it or not, Po,
you have to choose a successor.
Eh. Nothing about them
says "dragon" or "warrior."
You will know when you know.
How do I know when I know?
You know?
When I'm conflicted, I come here
to ask the universe for answers.
Just as Oogway did before me.
I'm not conflicted.
I'm just not ready for a next step.
What is that you're holding?
The Staff of Wisdom?
Other hand.
A chewed-up peach pit?
Exactly.
Every pit holds the promise
of a mighty tree.
Uh, how is this gonna help me
find the answers?
Don't ask me. Ask the universe.
Be the pit, Po. Be the pit.
There we go.
All right, universe.
Give me some guidance.
Inner peace.
Dinner, please.
Dinner with peas.
Snow peas?
In a sesame soy glaze.
Inner peace.
This is not working at all.
Maybe focus on your breathing?
I'm trying, but it's kinda hard
when you keep talking to me.
Technically, you're talking to you,
if you think about it.
Hey, will you two be quiet?
I'm trying to concentrate here.
Wait, if I'm Po's inner voice,
then who are you?
Uh, I'm Po's inner, inner voice.
How many voices do I have in there?
- You do not want to know.
- This dirt is itchy.
- I just love kung fu.
- What am I gonna be?
- Are we alone in the universe?
- You guys thought it was awesome, right?
Anyone want a cookie?
Universe?
Is that you?
Attention, mysterious figure!
The Dragon Warrior's here
to perform justice.
I know you're in here.
Just a matter of time before I find you.
Ooh.
You can't hide from justice forever.
The Dagger of Deng Wa.
You've got excellent taste,
I'll give you that.
But I can't give you that.
Give it back.
If you insist.
- Oh, no!
He's got a walking stick.
What are you gonna do? Stroll me to death?
This stick is not for the strolling.
It's the Staff of Wisdom.
The Dragon Warrior is gonna be mad
when he finds out you took his stick.
I am the Dragon Warrior.
I'm just gonna say it. Nothing about you
says "dragon" or "warrior."
Whoa.
Hi-yah!
How dare you desecrate the Hall of Heroes?
Who's desecrating what now?
Master Ostrich's Egg!
Oops, my bad. Hi-yah!
The Indestructible Chain Hammer
of Master Pangolin.
Whoopsies.
Ha-ha! [grunts] Oh!
The Urn of Whispering Warriors!
Which I've already broken! Twice!
Why would you keep an urn of souls?
Feels kinda creepy.
Are you doing okay there, big guy?
You're looking a little tired.
- I've never felt more awake!
The War Hammer of Master Chipmunk?
You're gonna pay for that.
Hello?
You faker.
It's not faking. It's called Method.
Catch ya later, panda.
No.
I think I'll catch you now.
Whoa!
Told ya.
You got me,
oh-great-and-powerful Dumpling Warrior.
That's Dragon Warrior--
Let go of me.
Just tell me one thing.
How did someone like you
become the Dragon Warrior?
That's a mystery for you to solve
during your two-year stay
at the Valley of Peace prison.
Valley of Peace prison?
Sounds like a day care.
It is a day care on the weekends.
But it's also a prison.
There he is!
Dragon Warrior!
Tai Lung is back.
- Tai Lung has returned?
He demanded all of our iron,
then destroyed our quarry.
- He's supposed to be in the Spirit Realm.
- Well, he's back.
He said that he's not gonna stop
until the Valley of Peace falls
and the Dragon Warrior
bows before him.
- He's back.
- Please, you've got to do something.
Looks like I'm not the only one
around here with a mystery to solve.
Well, you know what they say...
every step leaves a footprint,
no matter how small.
Every step leaves a footprint,
Very clever, fox. You know something.
Maybe I do, maybe I don't.
Okay, I do. I really, really do.
- Tell me.
- And why should I?
I mean, what's in it for me?
The peace of mind
knowing you did the right thing.
You're adorable.
Has anyone ever told you that?
And I don't mean just in, like,
the cuddly sense.
I don't have time for games.
Tai Lung is running loose
in the Valley of Peace.
Maybe. Or maybe she wants you to think
it was Tai Lung.
Wait. She?
Mine!
The Empress of Disguise,
capable of taking any form,
mimicking any shape.
The master of deception.
The lizard of lies
with the glowing teal eyes.
I'm talking 'bout...
The Chameleon.
This is kind of a private conversation.
Who's The Chameleon?
Only the most powerful
shape-shifting sorceress.
So she shape-shifted into Tai Lung.
But what does she have against me
and the Valley of Peace?
These are good questions.
You should ask her.
You're right.
How do I find this "The Chameleon"?
She isn't someone who can be found.
At least not without someone in the know.
And how do I find someone "in the know"?
Oh! It's me.
It's obviously-- It's me.
I'm in the know.
Forget it. I'll find her on my own.
Good luck.
After all, how hard can it be
to find someone who can look like anyone,
blend in anywhere?
Fine. You lead me to The Chameleon,
and I'll see what I can do
about reducing your sentence.
Deal.
Po!
What do you think you're doing?
There's this shape-shifting
sorceress on the loose and--
That's a job for the Furious Five.
Well, they're not here, and someone
needs to protect the Valley of Peace.
Look, I know that change is difficult
and that you enjoy
being the Dragon Warrior,
but your job is finding a successor.
The Dragon Warrior and I have a deal.
Mind your own business, squirrel.
Master Shifu is not a squirrel.
I'm a red panda.
You know what? I love that for you.
Po, this is your decision.
But I think you know what choice
Master Oogway would want you to make.
- Thanks for the free stay.
What are you doing?
- Little dank for a day care.
- Wait!
- Not bad for a jail.
- Where is she going?
You can't leave.
Don't worry, I'll have her back
before you even know she was gone.
You are supposed to be
passing along wisdom and inspiring hope!
Just think of it as
one last Dragon Warrior adventure.
I'll be back soon.
Tell my dads I love 'em.
- I can't hear you anymore! Bye!
Yeah! It sure is good
to be a free fox again.
That's a good back scratcher.
- Yoink!
- Hey!
So, does this really unlock the door
to the Spirit Realm?
It doesn't work like that.
It has to be given
in order to gain its powers.
Gotcha. Given to gain.
So, can I have it?
No! What do you take me for?
An easy mark.
What's an easy mark?
Someone who's easy to steal from,
usually because they're generous
and too trusting.
- Like you.
- Aw, thank you.
I heard The Chameleon is a monster
with an appetite of a thousand predators,
and her favorite food is panda.
They say this Chameleon character
has magical powers.
If you say her name three times,
she'll take you away in the night!
The Chameleon can shape-shift
to look like anyone, even you.
Or you.
Mr. Li! Mr. Li! Is it true?
Po's going to
take down an evil sorceress?
The-- The Chameleon?
Well, a Dragon Warrior's work
is never done.
Li, I'm thinking Po teaming up
with a convicted felon
to take down an evil sorceress
wasn't such a great idea.
Relax. Po has faced demons, demigods,
and everything else in between.
He's always come out on top.
You're right. You're right.
But what if you're wrong?
Calm down, Ping.
How bad can one evil sorceress be?
Who is she to summon us?
Classic power move.
We're the heads of Juniper City's
most prominent crime families.
And she's just some bug-eyed,
power-hungry reptilian runt.
You left out the evil sorceress part.
We used to run this city.
Now we pay her half the money we swindle.
It's like a criminal can't
make an honest living anymore.
Yeah, but what could we do?
Together, we can take her down.
- Are you nuts? She's a shape-shifter.
She could be at this very table,
and we'd have no idea.
For all we know,
you're The Chameleon.
Or you're The Chameleon.
- Or maybe...
- Oh, no.
- Maybe...
- Don't say it.
...I'm The Chameleon.
I said don't say it.
We obviously spoke out of turn.
Sorry, Chameleon.
No, no. Don't apologize.
You and your families prospered
by preying upon the weak,
so it doesn't feel good
when you're the one being squeezed.
Especially when the one
doing the squeezing
is just a "bug-eyed, power-hungry"...
What was the rest?
Reptilian runt.
Well, this "reptilian runt" wants more.
You already have the city.
What else could you possibly want?
I have something special in mind.
I'm very close to achieving it.
As close as the blood moon.
But the blood moon
is two nights away.
So little time, so many expenses.
Which is why I'll need to increase
this month's tribute to 60%.
No.
What was that now?
I mean no disrespect.
Don't worry.
I forgive you for the impudence
and the backstabbing.
And the blatant disrespect
you've shown me, I forgive.
But I never forget.
You might say I have the memory...
Oh, don't say it.
...of an elephant.
You think
I've pushed you too far?
Then you, my friend, can't begin to fathom
just how far I can push.
I'll expect your tributes by dawn.
Are we gonna stop
for lunch soon?
Justice doesn't stop for lunch.
But it does take the occasional time-out
for snackage.
Wanna split my almond cookie?
You're just gonna give me half of your
cookie out of the goodness of your heart?
- Mm-hmm.
- What's the catch? The rub? The bamboozle?
The "bam-what-le"?
You know, the fleece.
The rook. The flimflam.
Do you want the cookie or not?
I got my eye on you.
How much farther is it
to this "The Chameleon"?
Just a little farther.
Li! What are you doing out here
in the middle of the night?
Well, I-- I-- I... didn't wanna miss
the blood moon rising.
Oh, pooh.
You are just as worried as I am.
All right, all right.
I know pandas come across as
calm, gentle and chill,
but... [chuckles] ...the truth is
I'm kinda freaking out!
So am I.
Po is just too calm, gentle and chill
to face a shape-shifting sorceress.
- What if he's captured?
- What if he's tortured?
Our baby!
Okay, okay.
Maybe Po has finally met his match,
but there is still something that he has
that The Chameleon does not.
- What's that?
- Us.
Now, let's go find our son.
I hope Po's okay.
You know, Li,
a wise goose once said,
"Worrying doesn't make
the broth boil any faster."
Who was that idiot?
Me, of course.
I was the wise goose.
Oh, yeah.
Whoa.
That's the biggest village I've ever seen.
That's no village.
That's Juniper City.
That's where I'll find
The Chameleon, huh?
Just a boat ride away.
And I'm gonna lead you
right to her front door.
Are you sure we'll find
a boat captain in there?
For the right price, those cutthroats will
take us anywhere we want to go.
Of course, we could always opt for
the four-finger discount.
No stealing.
"The Happy Bunny Tavern".
Well, that sounds inviting.
Anybody lose a rabbit?
Stir faster!
Welcome to the Happy Bunny Tavern.
I'll find us a ride.
Maybe you can get us some food.
And stay out of trouble.
Hey, what you guys playing?
Mah-jongg.
And the stakes are high.
Can I play?
Surely you'll go easy on a beginner,
'cause I'm very beginning.
- Hey there.
- What can I get you?
A boat ride to Juniper City.
Ask this guy.
- Who's he?
- He's the captain.
- Thanks.
Oh, I win again.
Beginner's luck, I guess.
Never played before, huh?
I'm sorry, are you accusing me
of cheating?
I would like to speak
to the manager, please.
I am the manager.
I'll give you a boat ride to Juniper City,
but I won't carry anything illegal.
I don't want any trouble.
Trouble runs from me.
Then it'll cost you double.
I'm confused.
Should I have said that I like trouble?
In that case, it'll cost you triple.
Oh. Uh, maybe we can go back
to the double price?
You got a deal.
Great.
Do I shake his hand or your hand?
Can I get anything else for you, ma'am?
Yes. Everything, again.
Except for the broth. It was very bland.
- Keep stirring!
Whoa! One of everything is my go-to order.
But how did you pay for this?
Legally. Lawfully. Fair and square.
- I'm proud of you.
Oh, wow! Look at the time.
Remember we have to do that thing
down by the place with that guy?
Did you actually think you could
grift a meal out of me?
There's gotta be some sort
of misunderstanding here.
And apparently,
I'm the one misunderstanding.
Please allow us to pay for our meal
and yours too.
I'm only hungry for...
- Dumplings?
- ...vengeance!
Well, then, come and get it.
No! No, no, no! Don't come and get it!
- Destroy them!
I got it!
There you go.
- All better.
- Come on! Gotcha.
Keep stirring!
Oh, yeah!
I'll take that.
Think this belongs to you.
No stealing!
Yeah, I think it's
a little too late for that.
It's never too late to do the right thing.
- Get them!
Watch out!
- Whoa!
- Skadoosh!
- Whoa. Nice move. You gotta teach me that.
You die, panda!
Ah! Uh.
Ah! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Who designs a tavern on a cliff?
I shouldn't have eaten
all those dumplings.
- Huh?
Uh-oh.
Sail ho!
Back up! Move, move, move!
- Not that I'm worried, but...
...what if The Chameleon knows
we're coming?
Why, she could be anywhere, anyone.
Li, would you please show
a little backbone?
I'm sorry, but bravery was never
really my specialty.
You don't have to be brave.
You just have to act brave.
Act brave? Got it.
- Ah!
- Oh!
Oh, Li!
- Hold on!
Hold me, Ping! It's all been for nothing!
Please, no.
- I'm too young!
How was that for acting brave?
Keep working on it.
Juniper City.
It's going to be great
to be back home again.
Does your family live there too?
They would. If I had a family.
It wasn't easy being a little fox
in a big city.
So I had to survive any way I could.
Hey!
Grifting. Shilling. Gaffing.
Stop running! Stop running!
Whoa, you're an orphan? So am I.
Well, I mean I was.
My goose dad adopted me,
and then later, my panda dad found me.
Goose dads, panda dads.
Guess it takes all kinds.
- Right, Mom?
Then, one day, a local took me in.
Put a roof over my head,
gave me clothes to wear, food to eat.
After that, I was never alone again.
I guess we both got lucky.
I guess.
Hey, tell me something.
Back in the Valley of Geese...
Peace.
...what did that angry little squirrel
mean...
Red panda.
...when he said you had to
find your successor?
Now that I'm supposed to become
Spiritual Leader,
I have to find a worthy successor
to take over as the Dragon Warrior.
Once you're on top,
that's where you wanna stay, right?
No, it's just that-- What do I know
about being a Spiritual Leader?
I can't even come up with
one of those cool-sounding proverbs.
"Life's greatest enemy is"...
Uh, I don't know. Stairs?
Okay.
Everyone knows
life's greatest enemy is time.
I guess it's just easier to hold on
to the life you know
than move on to the one you don't.
Hey, that was pretty good.
Yeah.
Maybe she should be the Spiritual Leader
of the Valley of Geese.
Whoa, that guy.
He drinks like a fish.
Should he be driving?
We've come to pay tribute,
as you requested.
Looks a little light.
Go back out and get me more!
More?
But-- But, Chameleon--
Go! Before I toss you
down another flight of stairs.
At last, my destiny approaches.
I'll expand my rule from Juniper City
to every city and town and village
from here to the Valley of Peace
and beyond!
They will all know the name
of The Chameleon!
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
Ah! Zhen! I had a vision.
I saw The Chameleon.
She's gonna take over cities and towns
and the Valley of Peace.
A vision?
While you were asleep?
I'm pretty sure that's just a dream.
Not a dream, a vision.
Either I had a bad dumpling
before I went to sleep,
or it's a Dragon Warrior thing.
We got to get to The Chameleon
and take her down.
Well, then you're in luck.
Welcome to Juniper City.
Whoa!
This is the place where you can be
whatever you wanna be,
do whatever you wanna do,
and steal whatever you wanna steal.
Uh, if that's your thing.
Land ho!
Whoa. That came out of nowhere.
Ah!
- Whoa!
- Move!
- Look out!
- Sorry!
Out of the way!
I've never seen so much traffic before.
You don't have rush hour
in the Valley of Peace?
No one's ever in that much of a rush. Oof.
Come on!
Well, sure is good to be home again.
The sights. The sounds.
The smells.
It's a wonton wonderland!
Yeah!
Po. Po!
Focus!
This city is the most amazing place
I've ever seen!
I used to feel the same way
until The Chameleon got her claws into it.
Tonight, we take down The Chameleon.
Oh, yeah.
I'll show you where this villainous
sorceress lurks as she dominates the city.
Is she lurking in that villainous tower
dominating the city?
How'd you know?
Eh, not my first time
taking down a villain.
Let's keep moving.
Hey, Zhen!
- Heya, Zhen.
Long time no see.
How you doing, Zhen?
Wow, you're quite the local celeb.
Yeah, well, let's just say
a face like mine is hard to forget.
What? You're a wanted criminal?
You sound surprised. Is this surprising?
I don't think this is surprising.
You never mentioned
you were wanted.
Don't worry.
The law has better things to do
than look for me.
- Hey, fox.
- We've been looking for you.
Must be a slow workweek.
I'll handle this.
Morning, officers.
Dragon Warrior here.
The fox and I are here
on official Dragon Warrior biz.
- Dragon who?
- Warrior what?
Dragon Warrior.
Anyone? Nothing?
Perhaps you know me better as...
the Kung Fu Panda!
- Wait, wait!
Can you believe that guy?
Aw, come on!
Okay, so we tried it your way.
Now we try it mine.
- Wait, what's your way--
Sorry.
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
You can't run away from the law.
You're a wanted criminal!
Yeah? Well, it looks like
I'm not the only one.
Wow. City life really is fast-paced.
We gotta get out of here
before they call for...
...backup.
That's a lot of bull.
- Run!
- Let's go, let's go!
- Oh!
Ow!
Let's go.
Whoa! Whoa!
I'm falling...
very slowly.
Ow!
Sorry.
Whew.
There they are!
We don't have time for a drum solo!
We're trapped.
It isn't much farther now.
You always say that,
and it's always so much farther.
Whoa. What is this place?
Home sweet home.
Some of the best crooks and criminals
in all of Juniper City live here.
Careful. These guys will steal your pants
right off ya, and you'll never know it.
Uh-oh.
Now, you kids be careful
with those fireworks.
Ooh!
Ow!
Oh!
So you're friends
with all these people?
They're practically family.
Zhen!
Oh! Is that really you?
Han, my old mentor.
I always knew someday you'll find your way
home back to the den.
And when you did...
...I'd be sure to give you
a proper homecoming.
Family, huh?
More like distant cousins.
All right. How should we do this?
Quick and painless?
Or slow and painful?
Slow and painful.
All right, you little scamps.
Slow and painful it is.
- Hooray!
- Yay!
You really don't wanna do this.
And why is that?
Because if you so much as
lay one claw on me,
you're gonna have to answer to...
the Dragon Warrior.
Warrior, warrior, warrior,
warrior, warrior.
Who?
Oh, man. Are my adventures
really that regional?
Introduce them, Po,
to your fists.
Remember, Po, there are other ways
to bring peace than by kicking butt.
Ah, come on. Really? Now?
Yes, now.
Hold on. Shouldn't my inner Shifus
have differing opinions?
We are in total agreement...
...with our mutual disappointment...
...in you.
Wait.
He who resorts to violence now...
will only find more violence later.
Huh?
So what you're saying is,
if we don't hurt Zhen a little now...
We can hurt her a lot later.
What? No, that's not what I said.
Yes! And more violence later
is better than less violence now.
No, no. I think you're misunderstanding
the fundamental point of--
- More violence!
- Hooray!
Violence makes my tummy tingle.
You know, that panda
makes a lot of good points.
- I like it.
Violence, violence, violence.
No, no, no! Wait!
Come back!
I'll come up with better wisdom.
You have got to workshop
those proverbs.
Uh, the Kung Fu Panda?
- Nope.
The son of Mr. Ping and Li?
Those are both very common names.
- Mentored by Oogway?
- Sorry.
Trained by Master Shifu?
- Oh! Master Shifu? Yes.
- Aha!
Everyone's heard of
the legendary Master Shifu.
But not you.
Did someone say "legendary"?
Bring it in.
Look, Han.
I know we've had our differences,
but I'm really in a jam here,
and I was hoping
you could help me out.
- Thank you.
- Don't drink that.
Oh!
We just need someplace to lie low
for a while until the heat cools off.
And why should I help you?
Because deep down
beneath that iron-scaled exterior
is a good-hearted soul
who still thinks of me
as one of the family?
Fine.
But if you're still here by nightfall,
I'm calling the bulls myself.
Sleep tight.
So tonight, we take down The Chameleon.
After you get your pants back.
Not cool! You guys--
Come on! Give them back.
Those are custom.
Yeah, this place doesn't
look very friendly.
Oh! Oh, my tail.
I'm sure everything is fine.
This is a restaurant.
These are my people.
We speak the same language.
You wait here.
Salutations!
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
I know you're having a good time,
but I was wondering if a panda
happened to be passing by these parts?
There was a panda here.
You know him?
Know him? Why, I'm his dad!
No, no, no, no, no, no. Hmm?
You need to pay
for what your son did to my tavern.
My boy wouldn't have done this
for no reason.
Is it possible your broth was bland?
Try it.
No, no!
The broth smells excellent.
You should not add a single thing,
especially not me!
Hands off the goose.
The panda's back.
- He's back?
No.
But you're about to wish he was,
'cause if you think he made a mess
of this place,
you have no idea what I'm capable of.
Everything he learned, he learned from me.
Except one thing.
Mercy.
I don't know where he got that,
because I don't believe in it.
Now, this can go one of two ways.
The easy way,
in which you tell me where he is,
or the hard way,
but it's hard to understand
what you're saying
because you have no teeth.
Mah-jongg.
I eat mah-jongg tiles for breakfast!
Huh?
Stay there!
Where's our son?
He took a boat to Juniper City.
Which way?
You know, a wise goose once--
Time to go.
Uh, yeah. Right.
Okay, let's try this again.
Stir the pot, roll the wok,
serve the dish, and ska-blam!
Hey, where's the golden dragon
that's supposed to shoot out?
Not gonna happen with a broom.
Yeah? Still not bad though.
Yeah. But stir later, roll higher,
and the word is "skadoosh."
"Skadoosh" isn't a word.
- And "ska-blam" is?
Ska-blam!
I gotta say, you're not
like any of the other masters I've met.
Yeah, I know.
There's not a lot of pandas.
No, you're, like, a good guy.
Listen up. The coast is clear.
Thieves, hit the streets.
And you two,
get out of my sight.
Huh?
I know I promised that I'd lead you
right to The Chameleon's front door,
but the back door seems
a little more practical.
I gotta say, Zhen,
you really are a fox of your word.
A chewed-up peach pit?
One from Master Oogway's peach tree
of heavenly wisdom.
Eh, it's a Valley of Peace thing.
It's supposed to remind me that every pit
holds the promise of a mighty tree.
Maybe it'll do the same for you.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
As a wise Spiritual Leader once said,
how may one kick butt,
if one doesn't seek a butt to kick?
You're a real piece of work,
you know that?
Thank you.
Wait, was that a compliment or an insult?
Yes.
Whoa.
Have you seen our son?
- Sorry.
- Nope.
- Nah.
Tell us you've seen our son.
Wait, why are they leaving? You said yes.
Hey, look. Po was here.
Amazing, Li, but how can you tell?
Oh, we pandas have a gift
for seeing what others cannot.
Come on. There may be more clues up ahead.
Why?
That was close.
Look out!
Huh?
- Po!
- Stand back.
- Whoa!
- They're coming!
- Hurry! Help me lift the cage!
It's no use.
- We gotta brace it with something.
- Here, use my staff.
All right, stand back. Here I go.
Zhen?
Where are you taking my staff?
I think you mean my staff?
You gave it to Zhen,
and now Zhen has given it to me.
"Given to gain,"
I believe, is how it works?
You were right, Zhen.
He was an easy mark.
Zhen...
First rule of the streets:
Never trust anyone.
I taught her that.
And you thought my apprentice
was your friend?
Apprentice?
She's the one that took you in?
Best thing that ever happened to her.
You should have seen
the little guttersnipe before I found her.
Mangy and half-starved,
hanging out with those rejects
from the Den of Thieves.
She had no fear.
Such potential.
So I took her in.
I made her what she is today.
Stand up straight.
Yes, master.
So you went through all of this just to
get me to give you the Staff of Wisdom?
Why?
I, too, came from humble beginnings
and dreamed of becoming something more.
I wanted respect and power.
I wanted to be a master of kung fu.
Say what?
I was turned away
from every training hall I went to.
They would say I was too small, too lowly,
and that kung fu was not my destiny.
And so, I chose a different path.
Sorcery.
I grew.
I excelled.
And I got everything
I had ever dreamed of.
- Everything except kung fu.
Just because I can look like Tai Lung
doesn't mean I can fight like him.
You see, Po, kung fu may be
performed by the body,
but its secrets are housed in the spirit.
And now that I have access
to the Spirit Realm--
You're gonna steal Tai Lung's kung fu.
His and those of every master villain
that came before me.
And once I do, no one will dare
underestimate me again.
You forgot about me.
Don't bother, Po.
Those bars are enchanted with
some very old and very powerful magic.
You'd need at least ten Dragon Warriors
to get through them.
Then I won't go through them.
I'll go under them.
Well, that's frustrating
for all sorts of reasons.
Whoa!
- Po!
- Zhen?
My staff! Hand it over.
I'm so sorry I lied to you.
I was just doing what I was told.
Apologize later.
Right now, I have to stop The Chameleon.
Po!
Zhen?
No!
Well done, Zhen.
You never said you were gonna hurt him.
What's the second rule
of the streets?
Someone always gets hurt.
And make sure it's never you.
I just wish there had been another way.
Third rule of the streets?
Third rule?
Some would say
it's the most important:
No one is interested in your feelings.
Chop-chop!
We have a Spirit Realm to plunder.
And smile.
Nobody likes a grouch.
Honestly, Zhen, I don't know where
you pick up such bad habits.
If I could--
Hey there.
Whoa!
Get off me! Ow! Ow!
Son!
- Now save me.
Hi, Son.
It's okay. We've got you, Po.
We've got you.
So you followed me.
- It was his idea.
Okay, okay. It was both our ideas.
We only follow because we love.
No, you followed
because you didn't believe in me.
And because we love?
Well, you're right.
I screwed up big-time.
I trusted the wrong person.
I gave the Staff of Wisdom
right to The Chameleon.
Oh...
Po, that was a very big-time screw-up.
If only I'd listened to Master Shifu
and stayed in the Valley of Peace,
The Chameleon wouldn't have my staff,
and none of this would be happening.
I was just so determined
to keep things the way they were.
Everyone is afraid of change, Po.
Even me.
There was a time not so long ago
when all I wanted to be was
the greatest noodle chef in the valley.
So what happened?
I became the greatest noodle chef
in the valley.
It's true.
But I also became a father.
And nothing...
nothing's ever been the same since.
Change doesn't always
have to be a bad thing.
Why do you think I always change
the menu at the restaurant?
Because if things stayed the same forever,
sooner or later,
they would lose their flavor.
He's right, Po.
Since I left my village,
I've become a bit of a warrior.
- Strong. Brave.
Move it.
This way.
Get those cages up there. Come on.
Hmm. This looks bad.
Really bad.
Move it.
Come on.
Don't tell me you were actually starting
to become friends with that panda.
What? No. It's-It's just--
When we want something, we must use
whatever is at our disposal to get it.
That's all that panda was,
something to use.
Is that why you took me in?
So I could help you get what you wanted?
Zhen.
I took you in because you were clever
and ruthless and unsentimental,
like me.
And the day you stop being those things
is the day when, yes,
you stop being useful to me.
So for both of our sakes,
don't change.
Tonight, when the blood moon rises
to its highest point in the night sky,
I will open the door to the Spirit Realm,
and all of its secrets will be mine!
Does the blood moon
always rise this slowly?
I seem to remember it rising faster.
No?
Just me?
Hmm.
Ugh.
It's just for dramatic effect anyway.
I think I'm just gonna
open the Spirit Realm now.
Bring me Tai Lung!
Tai Lung.
Big fan.
Who are you,
and what are you doing with that staff?
This was given to me
by an old friend of yours.
The puffy panda?
Po might be an idiot,
but he'd never willingly hand over
Oogway's staff to the likes of you.
Who said anything about willingly?
Hmm. Apparently I misjudged you, lizard.
Now, why have you brought me back?
I summoned you here
so that you could teach me
your most legendary kung fu moves.
I don't share my skills with anyone.
It wasn't a request.
Yes, I got it!
The Tai Lung nerve strike.
The power, the precision.
What have you done to me?
All of your kung fu is now mine.
And the best part is,
I'm just getting warmed up.
Bring me General Kai.
Bring me Master Osprey.
Master Bull.
Po, wait!
Please be reasonable.
I'm not going anywhere
until I get my staff back.
No staff is worth your life.
As long as I'm still the Dragon Warrior,
I won't let anyone else get hurt
because of me.
Po!
You're alive!
Please. I made a mistake.
So did I. Trusting you.
I'm sorry.
Did your master tell you
to say that too?
She's not my master.
I'm leaving, for good.
It's the truth.
I was wrong about everything.
- What are you doing?
Stopping you.
Get out of my way, Zhen.
No.
Move.
You want me to move?
Move me.
First you betray me,
and now you wanna fight me?
- Why are you doing this?
To stop you from getting killed.
What do you care
if I get killed or not?
Please, Po.
Just let me do one thing right.
You're not the only one
who's made some bad choices lately.
You're really gonna
go through with this, aren't you?
'Fraid so.
And there's nothing I can do
to talk you out of it?
I'm afraid not.
You can't beat her, you know.
You're probably right.
But I have to try.
Get as far away from this place
as you can.
Po!
We should never have
let him come here.
We are such terrible fathers.
At least you didn't lie and betray him.
Well, that's true.
You're worse.
I am a terrible friend.
"Friend"?
That feels a little generous, no?
Uh, l-let's just give up.
Surrender.
We can't let him go in there alone.
What can we do?
There are just three of us
against an army.
Then I guess we'll just have to
get an army of our own.
Hey! Listen up, everybody!
Quack!
Thank you.
The Dragon Warrior's in trouble.
- Who?
- You know, Po.
The panda.
No, no. A different panda.
- I'm his father.
- I'm also his father.
Okay, that doesn't matter.
What matters is that my friend's
in trouble and he needs my help.
So, I need yours.
Why should we help you?
Because--
Because...
it's the right thing to do.
Stop it. Stop.
Stop laughing.
Look, I know you think
it might be too late
for a bunch of cheats, thieves and
cutthroats like us to change our ways,
but a good friend once told me
it's never too late to do the right thing.
So what you're saying is,
the more right we do now,
the more wrong we can do later.
- What? No.
And with The Chameleon out of the way...
We can finally do all the wrong we want.
I-I think you're missing
the fundamental point.
Violence, violence, violence.
Are you guys ready to do the right thing
for the wrong reasons?
Now, you see, this mistake
this Dragon Warrior fellow made
was underestimating his opponent.
I never would have walked
into such an obvious trap.
Hey.
Now, you see, the mistake
this Dragon Warrior fellow made was that--
Shut up, Larry.
This place is crawling
with more guards than I've ever seen.
I'm never gonna get to Po in time.
You just get to Po.
We'll take care of the guards.
We will?
I-I mean, we will.
But how?
Just leave that to me.
General Kai?
Lord Shen?
Those are all my old nemesis-es.
Nemes-ee. Nemes-i?
The Chameleon is pulling spirits
from the Spirit Realm
and draining us of all our moves.
And she's using your staff to do it.
- I'm here to get it back.
I won't hold my breath.
Um, I'm sorry, do I know you?
Do you know me? It's Scott.
The fire-breathing crocodile?
Oh, right! Scott!
Master Shifu and I
were just talking about you.
Panda.
Oogway made a mistake
choosing you as the Dragon Warrior.
I just didn't realize
how big a mistake it was until now.
Whoa. Tai Lung?
I'm gonna get that staff back,
restore your kung fu,
and return you all
back to the Spirit Realm.
You'll see.
All I see
is a broken promise.
All right, you bunch of
cantankerous Komodos.
Now, this can go one of two ways.
The easy way,
in which you surrender willingly,
or the hard way,
where you surrender woundedly.
The choice is yours.
- I was kidding! I was kidding!
Aw.
- Ow! Ow!
Thanks, Ping.
Run away!
Cannonball!
- Oh, is it too spicy?
Mmm. No. It's got the perfect kick.
Ginseng. That's the secret
to my mulberry punch.
That panda was right.
More violence later is better!
Yay!
I believe you have something
that belongs to me.
Can't you even die right?
Can't you even kill wrong?
No.
Wordplay didn't come together.
Now, about that staff...
Take it.
I already have everything I need
from it anyway.
I think this was destiny.
A final face-off
between formidable adversaries,
alike in so many ways.
If only I had a dumpling for every time
a villain told me
how much we had in common.
It's true.
We've both risen
to the highest of heights.
It's a shame only one of us can
come out on top.
It is a shame, for you.
My combined powers of sorcery and kung fu
make me unstoppable.
And once I dispense with you,
I'll expand my rule from Juniper City to--
Every other city and town and village
from here to the Valley of Peace
and beyond.
Yeah, I know.
But how did you know?
I saw it in a vision
because I'm the Dragon Warrior...
for now at least.
But I've realized
that it's probably time I made a change.
And so should you.
I'm The Chameleon.
I do nothing but change.
Only on the outside.
Real change happens from within.
And if we're really as alike as you say,
then maybe we could both let go
of who we were
and become something better
than we already are.
- What do you say?
- I say...
Well, I saw that coming.
We're very proud of you.
You tried it our way.
Now try it yours.
Kick her butt.
I'm way ahead of you.
Master Elephant's Trunk Twist.
Master Boar's Tusks of Terror.
Master Wolf's Fangs of Fury.
Master Bull's Horns of Doom.
What?
Recognize this move?
Is that how I sound?
I don't sound like that, do I?
You didn't earn those skills.
You just stole them!
Give him a left, a right, uppercut.
- Which one are you rooting for?
- I'm not sure. This is all very confusing.
I'm stronger than every opponent
you've ever faced,
because I am every opponent
you've ever faced.
Po!
Whoa. I gotta workshop
those heroic entrances.
Nah, it was just right.
I knew I should have left you
to rot in the gutter where you belong.
Better to rot in the gutter
than under your thumb.
- Two against one?
Well, now, that doesn't seem fair.
I'll have to even the odds.
Master Cobra.
Master Osprey.
Master Scorpion.
Master Wolf.
General Kai.
Lord Shen.
That is awesome!
I mean, it's disturbing, but it's awesome.
Whoa!
Zhen!
No!
Whoa, whoa!
Po!
I thought we were friends.
Stand back.
I'm gonna kick my butt.
Come on, Po, get out of there.
- You have to do this.
- I can't beat The Chameleon.
A wise, old tortoise once told me
that you never know what you can do
until you do it.
The fate of the world
hangs in the balance,
and you're here giving me life advice
from a tortoise?
Be the pit, Zhen.
Be the pit.
And what do you think you're doing?
Finishing what Po started.
Oh, please. How many times
do I have to tell you?
Don't slouch.
You ungrateful little urchin.
After all I've done for you,
you betrayed me for the panda?
First rule
of the streets: Never trust anyone.
Ha! You can't defeat me.
I know all your moves.
Not this one.
Roll, stir, serve,
and ska-blam!
Yes!
Second rule: Someone always gets hurt.
Now, that's a cool move.
Po! You could have gotten out of that cage
anytime you wanted?
You faker.
It's not faking. It's Method.
Besides, how's a peach pit
ever supposed to become a tree
if you never give it
the chance to grow?
And, hey, you stirred faster
and rolled higher.
But for the last time, the word is...
..."skadoosh."
Maybe Oogway was right about you.
You aren't completely useless after all.
Oh, my gosh.
Thank you so much.
That's my son.
Our son.
I think it's time you send us home, panda.
Zhen, do something!
Third rule:
No one's interested in your feelings.
See you on the other side, Dragon Warrior.
We packed some food
for your time in jail.
Let's hope it's not
your final meal.
Thanks, guys.
I was thinking, after I serve my time
and I'm a free fox again,
maybe I'll open one of those
acupuncture places that are all the rage.
I think you're better suited for a job
with a little more room for growth.
Jade Palace?
Her?
Out of all the candidates you choose
to train as your worthy successor,
you chose the fox?
You know when you know,
you know?
Fine, choose who you want.
A thief, a stick, a carrot.
I don't even know why I bother.
I'm going to go meditate... a lot.
Don't worry. He'll come around.
Probably. Maybe.
Hey, you okay?
He's right.
What about me says I'm ready for this?
Well, as I learned
from working in my dad's kitchen,
sometimes the greatest dishes come
from the most unlikely ingredients.
Hey, that's not bad.
Okay, I see you, Spiritual Leader.
Yeah. I'm getting the hang of
this proverb thing.
One shouldn't do a deep squat
with a chopstick in one's pocket.
Maybe you should
just stick to kicking butt.
Money can't buy happiness,
but it sure can buy a lot of dumplings.
Why does it always come back
to dumplings with you?
When life gives you lemons,
make pear juice and blow everyone's minds.
We get it.
You can't have your mooncake
and eat it too.
Although, I guess you could have mooncake
and then order mango pudding on the side.
Can we just start the training now?
Inner peace.
Hey, Master Shifu.
Look, there's two of us.
- You're doing great, Shifu.
- You're not breathing with your belly.
- You look a little tired.
- Are you tired?
- You do look like a squirrel.
- Do you want a cookie?
Inner peace.
Are you ready to begin your training?
Are you?
Yes, and I brought a little help.
♪ Oh, baby, baby
How was I suppose to know ♪
Whoa.
♪ That somethin' wasn't right here ♪
Ow! Oh, it's hot! Hot, hot!
♪ And now you're out of sight, yeah ♪
♪ Show me, how you want it... ♪
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
♪ I need to know now, oh, because ♪
♪ My loneliness is killin' me, and I ♪
- ♪ I must confess, I still believe ♪
- ♪ Still believe ♪
♪ When I'm not with you, I lose my mind ♪
♪ Hit me, baby, one more time ♪
♪ Girl, you got me blinded ♪
♪ It's not the way I planned it ♪
♪ Show me how you want it to be ♪
♪ 'Cause I need to know now, oh, because ♪
♪ My loneliness is killin' me, and I ♪
- ♪ I must confess, I still believe ♪
- ♪ Still believe ♪
♪ When I'm not with you, I lose my mind ♪
♪ Give me a sign ♪
♪ Hit me, baby, one more time ♪
♪ Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby
Hit me one more time ♪
- ♪ Hit me, oh, yeah ♪
- ♪ Baby, baby, baby ♪
- ♪ One more time ♪
- ♪ Hit me ♪
♪ Hit me, baby, but not too hard ♪
♪ Hit me one more time ♪
♪ One more time, again ♪
♪ Oh, baby, baby ♪
♪ How was I suppose to know ♪
♪ That something wasn't right here ♪
♪ Oh, pretty baby
I shouldn't have let you go ♪
♪ And I must confess ♪
♪ That my loneliness ♪
♪ Is killing me now ♪
♪ Don't you know I still believe ♪
♪ That you will be here ♪
♪ And give me a sign ♪
♪ Hit me, baby, one more time ♪
♪ My loneliness is killing me, and I ♪
♪ I must confess, I still believe
Still believe ♪
♪ When I'm not with you I lose my mind ♪
♪ Give me a sign ♪
♪ Hit me, baby, one more time ♪
Provided by sash35
Modify by Blue-Bird™